Finding Aid to the Gloria Steinem papers SSC.MS.00237
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES IV. WRITINGS, 1957-97
  - Articles
    - Texts, alphabetically by title: may include drafts, galleys, and/or publications
      - How to Put Up With a Difficult Man, Glamour, Nov 1963; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 36)
      - How to Survive Though a Feminist, Ms., Jul 1978; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 37)
      - If Marilyn Had Lived, Cleo, Jun 1987; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 38)
      - If Men Could Menstruate, Ms., Oct 1978; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 39)
      - If the Shoe Doesn't Fit, Change the Foot, Ms., Feb 1977; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 40)
      - If We Lived Here, Daddy, You'd be Home by Now, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 41)
      - If We're So Smart, Why Aren't We Rich?, Ms., Oct 1973; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 42)
      - I Love Work, I Love Power, I Love Success, New York Times Magazine, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 43)
      - Imagining Eva and Isabel, 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 44)
      - The Importance of Ms. Magazine, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 45)
      - Incest: Personal Testimonies, Gazette, 1977; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 46)
      - An Incompleat but Highly Personal Guide to Social Differentiation in New York, G.Q., n.d.; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 47)
      - In Praise of Women's Bodies, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 48)
      - The Inner Man, Glamour, Mar 1968; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 49)
      - Inside the Press: the Search for Nixon's Doctor, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 50)
      - Inside the System, Ms., Jul 1977; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 51)
      - The International Crime of Genital Mutilation, Ms., Mar 1980; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 52)
      - The International Feminist Revolution, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 53)
      - Interview with Valerie Harper, Ms., May 1978; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 54)
      - In the Camp of the Radical Humanists, Radical Humanist, 30 Jun 1957; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 55)
      - Introduction, Lesbian Sourcebook, 1977; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 56)
      - Introduction to Marc Feigen Fasteau, The Male Machine NY: McGraw Hill, 1974; 1 folders (Box 112, Folder 57)
      - In Your Heart You Know He's Nixon, New York, Oct 1968; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 1)
      - Is Child Pornography about Sex?, Ms., Aug 1977; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 2)
      - Is There Sex after Sex Roles?, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 3)
      - Jackie Reconsidered, Literary Cavalcade, Dec 1983; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 4)
      - James Baldwin: An Original, Vogue, 1966-67; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 5)
      - Julie Andrews, Vogue, Mar 1965; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 6)
      - Kennedy Memorial, 1964; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 7)
      - Laboratory for Love Styles, New York, 16 Feb 1970; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 8)
      - Latin American Conference, 1978; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 9)
      - Leaps Forward: Post-Patriarchal Eating, 1990; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 10)
      - Learning from Scandalous Women, 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 11)
      - The Least Dangerous Game, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 12)
      - Lee Bouvier Comes Out, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 13)
      - LeFrak Way of Life, New York Times Magazine, 31 Jul 1966; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 14)
      - Letter to the Editor, JD [John Deere] Journal, Dec 1981; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 15)
      - Letter to Delegates from New York Citizens for McGovern, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 16)
      - Letter from Kerala, for Smith College Sophian, circa 1957; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 17)
      - Liberation, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 18)
      - Looking Around with Gloria Steinem, Look, Sep 1968; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 19)
      - Looking Backward...and Ahead, 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 20)
      - Malcolm X: Newsspot, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 21)
      - Manners and Games, Glamour, circa 1964; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 22)
      - Map of the Gender Gap, 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 23)
      - Marisol: The Face behind the Mask, Glamour, Jun 1964; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 24)
      - The McGovern Phenomenon, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 25)
      - Maurice Joseph Micklewhite (Michael Caine), New York Times Magazine, 4 Dec 1966; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 26)
      - Meet the Real New York, Glamour, Apr 1964; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 27)
      - Memoirs of a Good Father, Ms., 1987; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 28)
      - Men Talk About Love, Glamour, Nov 1964; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 29)
      - Miscellany, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 30)
      - Mobilizing for Women's Studies, Ms., Sep 1973; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 31)
      - The Moral Disarmament of Betty Coed, Esquire, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 32)
      - Mrs. Kennedy at the Moment, Esquire, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 33)
      - Ms. fragments, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 34)
      - Music, Music, Music, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 35)
      - The Myth of the Masculine Mystique, International Education, Spring 1972; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 36)
      - The Nazi Connection, Part II, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 37)
      - Nelson Rockefeller: The Sound of One Hand Clapping, New York, Aug 1969; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 38)
      - The New Place in the Sun, Glamour, Apr 1967; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 39)
      - New Yorker (letter), n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 40)
      - New York, I Love You, Glamour, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 41)
      - A Nice Healthy President, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 42)
      - Night Thoughts of a Media Watcher, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 43)
      - Ninth Birthday Personal Report, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 44)
      - 1964 Won't You Please Come In, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 45)
      - Noel Coward in Ham and Eggs, 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 46)
      - No More 'Just Learn your Sides, Man'..., New York Times, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 47)
      - Notes from the Cancer Ward, New York, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 48)
      - Notes on the New Marriage, New York, Jul 1968; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 49)
      - On The Press, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 50)
      - On the Re-Reading of A.A. Milne, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 51)
      - An Ordinary Woman, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 52)
      - Our Man is 'Real Boss,' New York Times, 28 Aug 1966; 1 folders (Box 113, Folder 53)
      - The Party, Vogue, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 1)
      - The Passionate Giver, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 2)
      - Paul Newman: Movie Star, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 3)
      - Paul Newman: The Trouble with Being Too Good Looking, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 4)
      - Paul Newman: Wherever he Goes, Things Happen, Chicago's American Magazine, Jun 1968; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 5)
      - People are Talking About Advance Notice, Vogue, 1963; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 6)
      - Personal Paths to Feminism, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 7)
      - Peter O'Toole, 1966; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 8)
      - A Plan for Improving Indo-American Relations in America, 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 9)
      - Poetic Deaths, or the Suicide Game, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 10)
      - The Politics of Food, Ms., Feb 1980; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 11)
      - The Politics of Journalism, Folio, Jan 1974; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 12)
      - The Politics of Talking, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 13)
      - Post-Election Diary, 1968; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 14)
      - Predictions: Global Feminism, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 15)
      - Preface, Quest, 1980; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 16)
      - President Chisholm, Ms., Jan 1973; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 17)
      - The Price You Pay, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 18)
      - Proustian Memories, The Poor Peoples, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 19)
      - Pudge, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 20)
      - Put Yourself First, Glamour, Jan 1965; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 21)
      - The Real New Yorkers, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 22)
      - Return of the Figure, Show, Jun 1962; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 23)
      - Richard Gere, 1985; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 24)
      - Richard Rovere's Ride, Herald Tribune, Jul 1962; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 25)
      - Ride the Sophistication Roller Coaster, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 26)
      - Rise of the Pink Collar Worker, Ms., Mar 1977; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 27)
      - Rooftop New York: What Goes on up There?, Ladies Home Journal, Jul 1965; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 28)
      - Room at the Bottom, Boredom on Top, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 29)
      - The Sari Is a Way of Life, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 30)
      - Saul Bellow, Glamour, Jul 1965; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 31)
      - Secrets of Deception, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 32)
      - Secrets of Mexico City, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 33)
      - Senior Spring, 1956; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 34)
      - Sex...and Music, New York Times, 8 Nov 1975; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 35)
      - Sexual Politics, Newsweek, Jul 1972; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 36)
      - Shake Your Head Three Times, Glamour, Jul 1964; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 37)
      - Shaw did Write 'Tootsie-Wootsie', New York Times, 12 Nov 1967; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 38)
      - She Will Not Vegetate in Gracie Mansion, New York Times Magazine, Jan 1966; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 39)
      - Show Business in Toledo, Feb 1962; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 40)
      - Sisters. Revolution. Sojourner. Ms., n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 41)
      - A Skeleton Key to Pop Culture, Life, 1965; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 42)
      - The Smartest Girl in New York, Glamour, Oct 1968; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 43)
      - Smith Girl Learns Much from India Experience, Smith College Sophian, Oct 1957; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 44)
      - Sonia Johnson in TRO, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 45)
      - Spot News, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 46)
      - A Starter List of Movie Classics, Ms., n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 47)
      - Some Suggested Fantasies to Have in the Sand, Show, May 1962; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 48)
      - Sophisticated Fun and Games, 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 49)
      - So You Want to be a Spy, Glamour, Sep 1964; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 50)
      - Speaking of Revolution: A Feminist Learns to Talk, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 51)
      - Student Prince, Esquire, Sep 1962; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 52)
      - Student Princess, Glamour, Aug 1966; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 53)
      - Subversive Dressing, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 54)
      - Suggestions for Vogue's America Issue, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 55)
      - Surrealism, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 56)
      - Take the Good Taste, Bad Taste Quiz, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 57)
      - Telephone Answering Service, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 58)
      - Tell Me, Linda, What in Your Background Led You to a Concentration Camp?, 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 59)
      - Testimony--Human Rights Commission, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 114, Folder 60)
      - That Woman in City Hall, New York, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 1)
      - These Are Not the Best Years of Your Life, Ms., Sep 1980; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 2)
      - Things to Say - and Not to Say - at Parties, 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 3)
      - Third World 'Lib' Hurting, Denver Post, 26 Jul 1975; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 4)
      - This Month, Show, 1962-63; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 5)
      - The Time Factor, Ms., Mar 1980; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 6)
      - Time magazine editorial, Jun 1980; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 7)
      - To Any Women Who Happened to Read 'And Now, A Word from Our Leader...', 1973; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 8)
      - Truman Capote, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 9)
      - Trying to Love Eugene, New York, Aug 1968; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 10)
      - Two Cheers for Egypt, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 11)
      - Unions, Black People, and Mrs. Onassis, New York, 16 Dec 1968; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 12)
      - Up From Powerlessness, The Sixties, 1977; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 13)
      - The Verbal Karate of Florynce R. Kennedy, Esq., Ms., Mar 1973; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 14)
      - A Very Special Party, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 15)
      - A Visit with Dorothy Parker ("for Ladies Home Journal Feb 1965"): unpublished (?) typescript, 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 16)
      - A Visit with Truman Capote, Glamour, Apr 1966; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 17)
      - Visiting Englishmen Are No Roses, New York Times Magazine, 29 Mar 1964; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 18)
      - Voices for Life, from Voices for Life: Reflections on the Human Condition, 1975; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 19)
      - The Way We Were, and Will Be, Ms., Dec 1979; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 20)
      - Western Women in India, Delhi Sunday Statesman, Oct 1957; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 21)
      - What Are We Waiting For?, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 22)
      - What Culture, Look, Nov 1968; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 23)
      - What Is a New Ms.?, Ms., Nov 1979; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 24)
      - What is Politics?, Women's Agenda, 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 25)
      - What is the Women's Movement?, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 26)
      - What It's Like to Be Married to Paul Newman, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 27)
      - What It Would Be Like if Women Win, Time, 31 Aug 1970; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 28)
      - What Playboy Doesn't Know About Women..., McCall's, Oct 1970; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 29)
      - What the Kennedy Family Taught Me, Glamour, Sep 1968; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 30)
      - What the U.S. Has to Learn About Women, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 31)
      - What We're All About, National Association of Mental Health Journal, Winter 1973; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 32)
      - What's in It for Me, Harper's, 1965; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 33)
      - When I Grow Up, Ms., Mar 1974; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 34)
      - White Male Losing Edge, Ms., 8 Nov 1975; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 35)
      - Who has the Higher Morals IQ... You or Your Mother?, Glamour, Nov 1965; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 36)
      - Who Voted for Richard Nixon?, 1972; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 37)
      - Why All Issues Are Women's Issues, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 38)
      - Why Do Women Work, Ms., Mar 1979; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 39)
      - Why Wealthy Women Also Need the Women's Movement, 1990; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 40)
      - Why We Need a Woman President in 1976, Look, Jan 1970; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 41)
      - Why Women Voted for Richard Nixon, Ms., Mar 1973; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 42)
      - Why Women Voters Can't Be Trusted, Ms., n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 43)
      - Why Women Work, Eastern [Airlines] Review, Jun 1979; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 44)
      - Will Women Make Carter a One-Term President?, Ms., Jan 1978; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 45)
      - A Woman for all Seasons: Margot Fonteyn, McCall's, May 1967; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 46)
      - Women and Power, New York, Dec 1968; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 47)
      - Women Composers, Marietta [Ohio] Times, 8 Nov 1975; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 48)
      - Women Could Decide the Election, View, 2 Nov 1980; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 49)
      - Women Rate Carter's First Year, 1977; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 50)
      - Women vs. War, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 51)
      - Women's Liberation Aims to Free Men, Too, Washington Post, Jun 1970; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 52)
      - Women's Lives Will Change, U.S. News and World Report, 1975; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 53)
      - Women's Unsung Talents, Elmira Telegram, 9 Nov 1975; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 54)
      - Wonder Woman, 1972; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 55)
      - Won't You Please Come In, 1964; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 56)
      - World Population Year article (includes interview with Dom Moreas), n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 57)
      - Writing for Films, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 58)
      - Unidentified manuscripts, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 115, Folder 59)
      - Unidentified manuscripts, n.d.; 3 folders (Box 116, Folder 1-3)
      - Untitled Script on California Farm Workers, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 116, Folder 4)
      - It's a Young Man's Games, n.d.; 1 folders (Box 116, Folder 5)
  - Research files: notes, clippings, correspondence, miscellany
    - Advice columns (never-published article for Redbook) (Box 117, Folder 1-2)
    - Ad piece (Box 117, Folder 3)
    - Bellow, Saul (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Body building (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - Capote, Truman (includes interview) (Box 117, Folder 6)
    - "Crazylegs" (women's stockings) (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - The Draft (Box 117, Folder 8)
    - The "Establishment": notes, clippings, printed material, 1964-67; undated (Box 117, Folder 9-10)
    - Feminist Federal Credit Union (Box 117, Folder 11)
    - Fonteyn, Margot (Box 117, Folder 12)
    - Gavin, James M. (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - General (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Hamer, Fannie Lou (includes interview) (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - India: notes and ideas (Box 118, Folder 4)
    - Jones, James Earl (includes interview) (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - Kennedy, Robert. (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Lindsay, John (Box 118, Folder 7)
    - Lindsay, Mary (Box 118, Folder 8)
    - MacLaine, Shirley (includes interview) (Box 118, Folder 9)
    - McCarthy, Eugene (Box 118, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 118, Folder 11)
    - Naisbitt, John and Patricia Aburdene (includes interview) (Box 118, Folder 12)
    - Newman, Paul and Joanne Woodward (Box 118, Folder 13)
    - Nixon, Richard: clippings, interview, press releases and schedules, and memoranda, 1968 (Box 118, Folder 14-16)
    - Percy, Charles (Box 118, Folder 17)
    - "Perfect Presidential Candidate," notes (Box 118, Folder 18)
    - Playboy (Box 118, Folder 19-20)
    - Presidential campaigns, 1968; 1984 (Box 118, Folder 21-22)
    - Radziwill, Lee (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Reagan, Ronald (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Romney, George (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Specific companies' ad policies (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Van Buren, Abigail (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Women's history (Box 119, Folder 7)
    - Women's magazine promotions (Box 119, Folder 8)
  - Books
    - The Beach Book: correspondence, congratulations (includes Gay Talese) and production material (includes draft of introduction by John Kenneth Galbraith), 1963-64; undated (Box 120, Folder 1-3)
    - Marilyn: articles, correspondence, financial and legal materials,foreign editions, research files, reviews, promotional tours, publicity, and manuscript materials 1985-87 [for master galley see SERIES X. OVERSIZE] (Box 120-123)
    - Moving Beyond Words: manuscript and galley pages, foreign editions, 1996 (Box 124-125)
    - Outrageous Acts and Everyday Rebellions: contracts, correspondence (includes Betty Ford), financial and legal material, foreign editions, tours, publicity, reviews and articles, manuscript drafts, galleys, author's copy and master copy, 1983-84 (Box 125-128)
    - Revolution From Within: clippings, correspondence, fact-checking references, foreign editions, proposal, research memoranda, manuscript drafts and fragments, galley, and researchfiles, 1980-90 (Box 129-138)
      [see also SERIES IX. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL]
  - Unpublished work: India by Air (a travel guide to India): correspondence, draft material, and related writings, 1959 (Box 138, Folder 10-25)
- SERIES V. ORGANIZATIONS, 1970-96
  This series includes materials pertaining to several organizations either founded by Steinem or in which she was an active participant. It is divided into eight subseries: International Women's Year; the Minnetonka Corporation (a cosmetics company organized in July 1986 at the Fifth Avenue offices of Calvin Klein); Ms. magazine and its allied philanthropic arms; the National Women's Political Caucus, Voters for Choice, the Women's Action Alliance, Women USA, and the Wonder Woman Foundation. These organizations are arranged alphabetically. For other organizations in which Steinem participated or maintained an interest, see SERIES VII. SUBJECTS.
  In 1972, the United Nations declared 1975 to be the International Year of the Woman. Steinem later described the 1975 conference, held in Mexico City, as "a kind of constitutional convention for women." After the conference, U.S. President Jimmy Carter convened the International Women's Year (IWY) Commission, whose task was to convene a representative conference in every state, and to elect delegates to attend the First National Women's Conference, held in Houston, Texas in November 1977. The conference drew 15,000 participants, who spent four days discussing and voting on twenty-six areas recommended by the state conferences. Records pertaining to Steinem's involvement with the IWY are scattered, but include minutes, memoranda and other material pertaining to the Houston convention and the drafting of the National Plan of Action.
  This series also includes Steinem's records pertaining to the Minnetonka Corporation, a cosmetics firm on whose Board of Directors Steinem served in the late 1980s. They include correspondence and memoranda, business and financial reports, board member briefing books, and miscellaneous related material
  Materials pertaining to Ms. are organized into two subseries: the publishing venture, Ms. magazine, and its philanthropic arm, the Ms. Foundation for Women. Ms. was spearheaded by Gloria Steinem and Brenda Feigen as a result of their experience with the Women's Action Alliance. Initially conceived as a newsletter to distribute information of interest to feminists, the idea evolved quickly into a national magazine. Pat Carbine, then an editor at McCall's, joined the project, and Ms. magazine was founded in 1972. Always embattled financially, in no small part due to difficulties obtaining advertisers, a plan emerged in the late 1970s to reorganize as a non-profit educational foundation that would operate under the auspices of the Ms. Foundation for Women. In 1979, the new entity was christened the Ms. Foundation for Education and Communication. Through the 1980s and to the present, the magazine has struggled financially, but has remained prominent as a voice of the contemporary feminist movement.
  The records of Ms. magazine include Advertising, Circulation and distribution, Editorial, Employees, Financial and legal, and Special projects. The largest of these, not surprisingly, is Editorial, which includes both letters from readers as well as correspondence with authors, in many cases filed together with the manuscript(s) under consideration. Prominent authors include Alice Walker, Andrea Dworkin, and Florynce Kennedy. Especially illuminating are the marginal notes Ms. staff added to manuscripts; these, like the in-house memoranda circulated among staff members, reflect both the collective editorial process and the perspectives brought to the magazine by its various editors, from which the Ms. perspective was forged. In addition to the picture captured here of the changing shape of feminism as it was conceived and advanced by the magazine, its authors, and its founders, the memoranda and correspondence shed light on some of the difficulties engendered by the non-hierarchical, feminist workplace the staff sought to create.